Congfeng Cao

Address Tsinghua Tongfang, Beijing, China

Email caocf@radi.ac.cn
Phone +86 13021919407

GitHub https://github.com/frfy
Personal Page https://byfrfy.plus/NLP
Blog https://byfrfy.top

Sex Male

I am currently working at Tsinghua Tongfang and mainly responsible for natural language processing research. At the same time, I am supervising the research work and progress of six other colleagues. I also have been cooperating closely with Peking University Health Science Center in medical text analysis. For the past decade, I have done lots of Machine Learning and deep learning research. As a result, I have a deep understanding of the basic theories and cutting-edge work of natural language processing, machine learning and deep learning. In addition, I have excellent programming skills especially in Python, C/C++ and Java.

EDUCATION

2014.9-2017.7	University of Chinese Academy of Sciences	
	MEng Signal and Information Processing	GPA: 3.58/4.0
2010.9-2014.7	Shandong Agricultural University	
	BEng Computer science and Technology	GPA: 3.5/4.0
	BEng Remote Sensing Science and Technology	GPA: 3.0/4.0

RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

2017.7-present Tsinghua Tongfang - team leader/programmer/PM

Knowledge Graph Products

- Completed the knowledge graph automatic construction tool and used natural language processing to realize automatic entity and relationship extraction.
- Embedded knowledge and graph.
- https://www.egov.thtf.com.cn/home/app/pingtaiview/article-id/1.html

Big Data Analysis and Decision Support Platform

- Established a platform combining data analysis and natural language processing.
- Categorized the text, extracted entities and extracted relationships.
- Associated the extracted entities such as economic indexes (GDP, CPI) with the data analysis platform and calculated weights of relationships using for making decision and prediction.

- The product is very popular among the governments to help them make decision and analyze the local economic development in many provinces in China such as Jiangsu and Hubei.
- https://www.egov.thtf.com.cn/home/app/pingtaiview/article id/2.html

Intelligent Government System

- Established a natural language processing platform that mainly implements topic model, text summary extraction, text similarity calculation, knowledge extraction and representation, recommendation and mining.
- Cooperated with the largest journal website in China (National Knowledge Infrastructure, CNKI) to mine journal articles and author information to complete relationship network of author and recommend articles in higher accuracy.

2018.1-2020.1 Peking University Health Science Center

The Chinese Medicine Question Answering System

- Established a Chinese medicine knowledge graph of drugs and symptoms from existing texts.
- Completed a question answering system for symptoms and drugs.

2018.7-2020.1 Communication University of China

The Public Opinion Analysis System

- Monitored accounts from social media (like Weibo, Facebook and Twitter) and crawl data
- Used deep learning and machine learning to classify and cluster, extract topics, perform sentiment analysis and event monitoring.
- Stored data (relationship, text) and visualized network data. (Neo4j, MongoDB, Highcharts).

2014.9-2017.7 Institute of Remote Sensing and Digital Earth, Chinese Academy of Sciences

Large Science Engineering Project-Multimodal Camera System

 Provided remote sensing image mosaic algorithms and image processing for the camera.

Lunar Exploration Project Phase III-Image Algorithm Module Image Database Design

• Used the database to store the original lunar image, the processed image by the algorithm, the algorithm parameters and performed the evaluation parameters of the algorithm quality.

Beijing Science and Technology Project-Development of UAVborne Multispectral Camera Based on Optical Filter Array

- Provided remote sensing image mosaic algorithm for the camera.
- Performed target detection and image segmentation on multispectral images.

PAPERS & THESES

2017 Research of UAV-borne Multispectral Camera System Based on Narrow Bandwidth Filter Array.

• Full text: https://byfrfy.plus/thesis.pdf

Abstract: https://byfrfy.plus/abstract.pdf

Congfeng Cao, Junyong Fang, Dong Zhao. Development of UAV-borne multispectral camera based on narrow band width filter array. OPTICAL TECHNIQUE, 2018, 44(1).

• Full text: https://byfrfy.plus/paper.pdf

HONOURS & AWARDS

2013.9-2014.7	Outstanding Student Scholarship
2014.9-2015.7	Academic Scholarship
2015.9-2016.7	Academic Scholarship
2016.9-2017.7	Academic Scholarship

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Machine Learning

- Programming experience with PyTorch (2 years) and TensorFlow (6 years) for deep learning applications.
- Experience with Artificial Neural Networks and the most recent Deep Learning architectures (e.g., ResNet, Bert, Transformer, GPT-3, XLNet, etc.).
- Experience with supervised, unsupervised learning algorithms, reinforcement learning, and Bayesian methods.
- Experience with the most important tools for Natural Language Processing and Computer Vision (e.g., Gensim, NLTK, OpenCV, etc.).

IT

2018

- Proficiency in Python (8 years, primary language). Used several programming languages such as C/C++, Java, R, Visual Basic, HTML, JavaScript, etc.
- Database (e.g., MongoDB, Oracle, MySQL, Redis, Neo4J, GraphDB PostgreSQL, etc.). NCRE: National Computer Rank Examination- Level 4 Database Engineer.
- Knowledge Graph tools (e.g., Apache Jena, OpenKE, Protege, etc.).
- Elasticsearch, Spark and related tools.
- Spider (Scrapy, pyspider).